■
本字幕由网络爱好者联盟原创翻译
欢迎加入我们 www.ZiMuZu.pub
在保留译者名单的前提下任何人不需要经得我们的同意
可用本字幕做任何用途因此所产生的后果由您自行承担
■
翻
译
吃薯条不想蘸酱
马丁马丁回音山
刺罗森林
Gashdany
■
翻
译
大大大大大爷
有鹿er
歪六六
■
校对
&
后期
青色桔子
大红
■
片头推广合作洽谈：请联系普罗米修斯邮箱 PLMXS2016@GmaiL.com
本英文字幕由explosiveskull提供
美第奇兄弟马戏团
快点  该走了  别磨磨蹭蹭的
Come on, time to go. We haven't got all day.
佛罗里达州  萨拉索塔市
1919年
把那只猴子赶上火车
Get that monkey on the train.
美第奇兄弟马戏团出发了
The Medici Brothers' circus is taking off!
即将光临
美第奇兄弟马戏团
牡马之星
霍特和安妮
美人鱼亚特兰蒂斯小姐
小凯西号
荣格
大力士
世界冠军
迷人巫师普拉德什
神奇动物
萨拉索塔市
莫尔特里河滨展览场
韦塔姆卡
斯塔克维尔
巴斯特普罗镇
瑟西市
乔普林市
小飞象
呼吸正常
Breathing normal...
心率正常
heart rate normal.
你可以上场表演了
You're cleared to perform.
米莉  又有一辆火车来了
Milly! Another train!
孩子们  等等  我们也要过去
Ninos, wait! We are coming, too!
乔普林市到了
Joplin!
密苏里州乔普林市
Joplin, Missouri!
-嘿  宝贝女儿  -爸爸
- Hey, sweetheart! - Daddy!
本来想跟你们说的
Oh, I meant to tell ya.
就在我寄回来的那些信里
You know, in the letter I sent?
很抱歉  那个时候我不在
I'm so sorry that I wasn't here.
快过来吧
Well, come here now.
我还是我
Still me.
你
And you...
你跟你妈妈一样好看
you're just as pretty as your momma.
爸爸  我们很想你
We missed you, Dad.
我也很想你们
I missed you, too.
伊万和凯瑟琳  谢谢你们两位
Ivan and Catherine, thank you both...
替我照看他们
for looking out for them.
这是我们该做的  法瑞尔上尉
Captain Farrier, of course.
别这样  叫我霍特就好
Oh, it's Holt, come on now.
叫我霍特就好
It's just Holt.
别担心
Don't you worry.
一切都会像以前一样
Everything's gonna be just like it was before.
快点  快点
Come on! Come on!
总算回家了
Home sweet home.
-嘿  霍特  -嘿  普克
- Hey! Holt! - Hey, Puck.
你好  托马斯
Hey, Thomas.
米莉  快点
Milly, come on!
你好  霍特
Hi, Holt.
你好  亚特兰蒂斯小姐
Oh! Hey, Miss Atlantis.
普拉德什
Pramesh!
亲爱的朋友  最棒的旅程
The very best journey, dear friend.
无异于踏上归家之路
The road that leads home.
欢迎回家
Welcome home.
别抱了
No hugs!
普拉德什  我也想你
Pramesh, I missed you, too.
怎么回事  营地怎么缩水了一半
What's going on? The camp's half the size it used to be.
时世艰难啊  朋友  大家都不好过
Hard times, my friend. For everyone.
各位请注意
Attention, everybody!
为什么说没有规矩  不成方圆
Why is Rule Number One called Rule Number One?
因为  锁好笼子
Because "keep the cages locked"
就是最重要的规矩
is the most important rule of all!
要是给我逮到
When I catch that fugitive scalawag
那个破坏我梦想的混蛋
who interrupted my dream...
荣格
Rongo!
荣格在哪儿
Where is Rongo?
是谁在负责管理营地
Who's heading camp management?
我只是个大力士
I'm the strongman.
没错  但是大家都得身兼数职
Yes, but we're all wearing multiple hats!
你得负责预算  记账  还有列清单
You're in charge of budgets, and accounting, and inventory.
也就是说你得负责动物的下落
Which means animal whereabouts!
现在立刻去把那只猴子找回来
Now, go find that monkey!
我去四处看看
I'll have a look around.
好了各位  回去工作吧
All right, everybody. Back to work.
霍特
Holt!
这个冬天的流感来势汹汹
This winter, the influenza hit us like a hurricane.
纳塔利娅  温琴佐
Natalya, Vincenzo...
范德吉一家  还有
the Vanderjees, and then...
你的妻子
your wife.
可怜的安妮
Poor Annie.
她顽强抵抗病魔
How she fought.
她是我们当中最优秀的
She was the best of us.
我知道
I know it.
为了她
So, uh, you know, for her,
我们要表演最好的一季
let's have our best season yet!
我的马呢
Now where's my horses?
这事儿说来有趣
Funny story about that.
怎么有趣
Funny how?
他把马卖了
He sold them.
但是我们的表演是马戏团的灵魂啊
But our act is the soul of this show!
然而先是你离开了
And first, we lost you,
接着安妮也走了  那些马没人骑
and then Annie, to ride 'em!
米莉也不肯学骑马
If only Milly would have learned the trade.
我不想在马戏团里出风头
I don't wanna be a show-off in your circus.
-出风头  -你听
- "Show-off"? - You see?
我想要研究科学
I wanna make scientific discoveries.
我要靠才智出名
I wanna be noticed for my mind.
好吧
Okay.
那就学学千里眼  读心术  什么都好
Then learn clairvoyance. Telepathy! Something!
我倒立能坚持十秒
I can do a handstand for almost ten seconds.
靠小孩倒立  七月份我们就得喝西北风
"Child does handstand." We'll be broke by July.
等等  没有马我要怎么表演
Hang on now. Without horses, what the hell's my act?
人们是涌来看我表演的
The crowds come to see me!
麦克斯  拜托
Max, please.
我需要工作
I need to work.
好消息
Good news.
我有一份工作
One job, I have.
那好  让我来场精彩表演
Okay, then. Give me a showstopper.
老麦克菲那个无赖
You know that old rascal Itchy McPhee?
他和胡子女士私奔跑路了
He finally ran off with the bearded lady.
之后我就只能找杂工来充当人手
I've been filling in with roustabouts ever since.
我需要有合适的人来照料大象
I need somebody good to tend the elephants.
不  你在开玩笑的吧
No, you're not serious.
谈正经事我不开玩笑
I am on occasion.
你知道的  这个工作很重要
This is a big job and you know it.
不  这是要我拿大铲子铲一大坨的
No, it's a big shovel for a big pile of...
爸
Dad.
你把我的马卖了  留下你的大象
So you sold my horses and kept your elephants.
那些脏兮兮  骨瘦如柴又低价的大象
Your scrawny, mangy, cut-rate elephants.
它们很重要  特别是在这一季
They're important. Especially this season.
怎么说
Why's that?
我知道这不是我的风格
I know it goes against my nature...
但这是我有史以来做的头一回投资
but for once, I made an investment.
漂亮小象  她在这儿呢
Bellissima! There she is!
全新的母亚洲象
Our brand-new Asian female.
我从比洛克西的布鲁贝克手上买下的
I bought her off a Brugelbecker in Biloxi.
我不得不跟他砍价
I had to get him way down on the price.
我跟你保证  霍特
But I swear to you, Holt,
她的眼神里隐含着不平凡的东西
I saw something special in her eyes.
这就是你说的投资吗
This is your investment?
一头年老病衰的大象
An old, sick elephant.
不  她没有生病
Oh, no. She's not sick.
不久之后
Any day now...
她就会生下一头象宝宝
she's having a baby.
爸爸  快看  我越来越熟练了
Dad, watch! Dad! I'm getting better!
等等  这就是我们的帐篷吗
Hang on now, this is our tent?
我们的东西哪去了
What happened to our things?
那些精美家具和房间呢
We had nice furniture, we had rooms.
麦克斯  你还把什么给卖了
Max, what didn't you sell?
真是个混蛋
You son of a gun.
爸爸  快看
Dad, look!
玩具
Toys?
这些不是玩具
They're not toys.
是我的科学实验工具
They're for my science experiments.
我们是马戏团  女儿  这里是马戏团
Well, we're a circus, darlin', a circus.
我们要想活下去就得务实一点
We need to be practical if we want to survive.
你不能开始学习表演吗  一个也行
You couldn't just take up one act?
翻筋斗  走绳索
Tumblin' or tightrope?
或许我不需要吸引全世界的目光
Maybe I don't need the world staring at me.
可能我就是不像你和妈妈
Maybe I'm just not you and Mom.
好吧  那这家里是谁说了算
Well, who makes the rules in this family?
妈妈说了算
Mom did.
好吧  那现在是我说了算
Yeah, well, I make them now.
所以  回你的房间去
So just, uh... Go to your room!
这就是我的房间
This is my room.
也是我们的房间
This is all our rooms.
看到没
See this?
知道这是什么吗
You know what this is?
这是给你们继承的遗产
It's your inheritance.
爸爸
Dad!
别担心  他会回来的
Don't worry, he's not going anywhere.
这个地方把他给困住了
He's stuck here.
就像困住我和你
Like you and me.
快点  快点  你要错过了
Come on, come on, you're missing it!
看  我可以  我真的可以  米莉
Look, I can do it! I'm doing it, Milly!
新的一季
A new season!
让我进去  你这个小毛球
Let me in, you little hairball!
谁能帮我进去我自己的车厢
Would somebody please let me in my own train?
爸爸  醒醒  我们走
Dad, wake up! Let's go!
我们得去帮帮大象
The elephants need us!
我的天  儿子
Good God, son,
你让我想起了打战
you're gonna make me miss the war.
这个给我
Gimme that.
走吧  带路
Go on, lead the way.
快走
Move it!
快走吧  珍宝女士
Let's skedaddle, Mrs. Jumbo!
别逼我动手
Don't make me have to incentivize.
快把她赶出来
Get her out of there, boys.
别急  鲁弗斯
Easy, Rufus.
里边可是头母象
That's a lady in there.
瞧瞧  有人来英雄救美了
Well, well, our own Tom Mix ridin' in to the rescue.
可惜他荣华不再了
But he just ain't on the marquee no more.
来看看他错过了什么
Time to see what he's been missing.
你感受到了吗
Do you ever get that feeling?
那种物是人非的感觉
Like there's something you're missing?
真是奇怪  你怎么没参军
Imagine my surprise, you didn't enlist.
心脏不好  医生说的
Weak ticker. Doc's advice.
爸  事情有点不对劲
Dad? Something's wrong.
她不想离开
She doesn't wanna leave.
快点
Come on!
我们把她弄出去
Let's get her outta there!
-你在做什么  -快点
- What are you doing? - Come on!
放开她
Leave her alone!
-求你别打她  -我说了让你别动她
- Stop hurting her, please! - Leave her alone!
爸  快看
Dad, look.
又怎么了
What now?
把她移走
Move her!
这里有个象宝宝
Whoa, we got a baby in here.
她生了个小宝宝
She had a baby!
小宝宝吗
Baby! Huh?
去通知报社
Notify the press!
美第奇兄弟马戏团
"The Medici Brothers...
荣幸给大家带来全美最新的
"proudly present America's newest,
珍贵快乐体验
"precious bundle of joy!"
快看
Look at that.
没事了
It's okay now.
别害怕
Don't be scared.
别怕  你的妈妈就在外面
Don't be scared now, your momma's right outside.
孩子  我们有个小宝宝了
Baby! We got a baby!
我们有小宝宝了
We got a baby!
那是个什么东西
What is that?
小珍宝
Baby Jumbo.
我的奇葩秀已经有很多伪奇葩了
I already got fake freaks in the freak show!
我不需要表演圈里有个真的
I don't need a real one in the center ring!
荣格  我们被骗了
Rongo! We've been swindled!
原来去买了个小怪物来
Gone and bought yourself a baby monster.
你觉得他能听见我说话吗
Think he can hear me?
荣格  给布鲁贝克发电报
Rongo! Telegram to Brugelbecker.
我们被劣质货骗了
"We have been bilked with damaged goods.
这是反常且扭曲的产物
"This is an aberration, travestation...
我得要回我的钱
"and I demand my money back."
但不管你做什么  别打电话给报社
But whatever you do, do not call the papers.
我们不会给这小东西打广告
We are not advertising this baby.
告诉我你还没打电话
Tell me you didn't do it.
你已经打了吗
You did it?
永远别在没跟我核对前
Never do anything I tell ya
就照我说的去做
without checking with me first!
为什么是我  为什么偏要是我
Why me? Why me?
长了张除了妈谁都不爱的脸
A face only a mother could love.
先生
Sir?
我们中也有不少人觉得您很帅气
Many of us find you handsome.
我说的是这象
I was talking about the elephant!
看  她要给他洗澡
Look, she's drawing him a bath.
得找个兽医来给他看看  麦克斯
Need a vet to come to look at him, Max.
不行  不能有人看见
No, no witnesses!
我们还有两周就要到乔普林了
We are going to be in Joplin for two weeks.
我们答应的是一个漂亮的宝宝
We promised them a beautiful baby!
你明晚之前要想办法解决
You have until tomorrow night to fix that!
-我吗  -对  就你
- Me? - Yes, you!
这是我的问题吗
This is my problem?
是啊  你照顾象群
Yes. You tend the elephants.
让那对耳朵消失
Make those ears disappear!
别看我
Don't look at me.
你看他  巨大的耳朵压得他抬不起头
Look at him, those giant ears weigh him down.
你好呀  小珍宝
Hi, Baby Jumbo.
欢迎来到马戏团
Welcome to the circus.
我们都是一家人  不管体型多小
We're all family here. No matter how small.
大象不是怕老鼠的吗
Aren't elephants afraid of mice?
谁说的  所以我们才要实验
Says who? That's why we experiment.
总有人要在他的妈妈不在时
Someone needs to keep him company.
陪在他身边
when he's not with his momma.
快看  也给他一个
Look. Give him one.
如果他能把耳朵移开就好
If he can lift his ears out of the way.
不  你得把耳朵吹到一边
No. You have to blow your ears out of the way.
像这样
Like this.
祝你好运了
Good luck with that.
搞不好你还能教他抛接呢
Maybe you can teach him to juggle, too.
小珍宝  看着我
Baby Jumbo, look at me.
跟我学着做
Do what I do.
吹
Blow.
不  别吹羽毛  吹你的耳朵  吹
No, not the feather. Your ears. Blow!
他觉得这是个游戏
He thinks it's a game.
-麦克斯  过来  -干嘛
- Oh, Max, come here. - What?
看这个
Watch this.
我滑出来  跳几下  然后突然间
I ride out, I do some jumps, then all of a sudden...
动物们全部窜出
stampede!
放动物
Send 'em!
让开  麦克斯
Get out of the way, Max!
我还在研究时间点
I'm, uh, still working out the timing.
让我也试试
Let me have a turn.
同时  给你
Meanwhile, for when you
-带大象出来的时候用  -什么
- lead out the elephants... - Uh-huh.
我让服装公司
I had the costume departments
给你做了点小东西
make you up a little something.
好吧
Okay.
我的天
What in gosh...
你真的为这个破费了  麦克斯
You really broke the bank with this, Max.
会有很多孩子来看演出
A lot of kids come to the show.
你不想让我吓到人  我懂
You don't want me to scare anyone, I get it.
爸爸  爸爸
Dad, Dad!
是小珍宝  快来看
It's Baby Jumbo. Come see.
他浮在空中了  用他的耳朵
He jumped in the air. With his ears.
孩子们  我说了别管他
Guys, I said leave him be.
但是他离地好高的
But he was this far off the ground!
可不是吗  我猜也是
Yeah, I bet he was.
他像那样会被耳朵绊着的
He'll be tripping all over with ears like that.
爸爸  是真的  我们做了个实验
Dad, really. We tried an experiment.
就别管那个可怜的小东西了
Just leave the poor guy alone.
科学守则第一条  你得感兴趣
First rule of science, you have to have interest.
否则  你就无法发现真理
Otherwise, you don't deserve to know.
对他俩来说今年都很不好过
It's been a rough year for both of them.
只有安妮知道怎么和他们沟通
Annie knew how to talk to 'em.
女士们  先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
小伙子们  小姑娘们  请上座
boys and girls, step right up.
快点  快来看
Hurry, hurry.
开看看今天的马戏表演
Come see the circus today.
解剖
之惊奇
现场
演示
"生存还是毁灭"
"To be or not to be...
"这是一个值得考虑的问题"
"that is the question.
"哪一种更高贵"
"Whether 'tis nobler in the mind
"默然忍受命运的暴虐的毒箭"
"to suffer the slings and arrows of outrageous..."
那才不是蛇
That ain't no snake.
妈的  我都能做到
Heck, I could do it.
那您请吧
As you wish.
快跑
Get out of here!
荣格  我们走
Rongo, let's go!
离那只小象远点
Hey, get away from the baby elephant!
欢迎各位乔普林和密苏里的来宾
Welcome, Joplin, Missouri!
女士们  先生们
Ladies and gentlemen...
我是你们的典礼大师
I am your Master of Ceremonies,
马克西米连·美第奇
Maximilian Medici.
现在  我将为大家介绍
And now, I give to you...
美第奇兄弟的马戏团
the Medici Brothers'  circus.
好了
Okay.
没事的  没人会伤害他的
Okay, okay, no one's gonna hurt him.
好了  小家伙  咱们表演去
Okay, little guy, let's put on a show.
那不是霍特·法瑞尔吗  那位牡马之星
Hey,  ain't  that Holt Farrier,  the  Stallion  Star?
你是霍特·法瑞尔吗
Hey! Ain't you Holt Farrier?
不  他在战争中死了  真是遗憾
Nah, he died in the war. So sad.
他在干什么
What's he doing?
他想去拿那羽毛
He's reaching for the feathers.
外套  外套  快穿上
Coat, coat, coat, coat!
大耳呆宝
你对他做了什么  那才不是真的大象
What'd you do to that thing? That ain't a real elephant.
耳朵是假的吧
Those ears are fake!
看  看那个标牌
Look! Look at the sign!
呆宝
"Dumbo!"
该词本意为傻子
冷静  快点
Whoa, calm down, now.
他是假的
He's a fake!
没错  他是假的
Yeah, he's a fake!
闭嘴
Shut up!
你们吓到大象们了
You're scaring the elephants!
放松  别紧张
Take it easy now. Calm down.
蠢货  傻子  冒牌货
Dumbo, Dumbo, fake, fake, fake!
好了  都坐下
All right, sit down.
蠢货  傻子  冒牌货
Dumbo, Dumbo, fake, fake, fake!
我说了坐下
I said sit down!
没关系的  小家伙
It's okay, little fella.
冒牌货
Fake!
荣格  起音乐
Rongo! Music!
欢乐  愉悦
Happiness, joy!
听说他们在嘲笑你家丑小子了吗
Hear 'em making fun of your ugly baby?
现在还有谁会帮他
Who's gonna help him now?
霍特  把那对耳朵给我弄台下去
Holt, get those ears off the stage!
好了  没事了
Okay, all right.
没事的  没人会伤害你的孩子
Okay, nobody's gonna hurt your baby.
先冷静下来
Just calm down.
冷静  乖丫头
Okay. Attagirl.
我们也在保护他  就和你一样
We're here to protect him. Same as you.
好姑娘
Attagirl.
乖乖的  放松点
Nice and easy.
没事的  没人会伤害你的孩子
Shh. Okay, nobody's gonna hurt your baby.
鲁弗斯  不要
Rufus, no!
-鲁弗斯  停下  -疯大象
- Rufus, stop! - Mad elephant!
给我回来
Get back!
麦克斯  把孩子们带出去
Max, get the kids out of here!
所有人  快走  到安全的地方去
Everybody, out! Get to safety.
小心  小心
Careful, careful.
孩子们
Kids?
走  走  走
Go, go, go!
快快快  走  走  走
Quick, quick, quick. Go, go, go.
快来  这边走  快点
Come on. This way , come on.
现在觉得你的工作怎么样啊  牛仔
How do you like your job now, cowboy?
米莉  乔  快点
Milly, Joe! Come on!
快走  快点
Let's go! Come on!
乔普林警察局
我想强调一下
And I wanna just emphasize,
我们没做错什么
we did everything right.
事情就是  帐篷倒了
What it is, the tent just absolutely fell down.
就是塌了
It just collapsed.
我们怎么知道会发生什么
And we had no way of knowing what was gonna happen.
疯象
bgm:Baby  Mine--Sharon Rooney
布鲁贝克  我的人死了一个
Brugelbecker, I have a man dead,
你知道吗
do you understand?
这就是从五大湖到海湾的人们所读到的
This is what they're reading from the Great Lakes to the Gulf!
马戏团的杀人野兽
你把那头杀人大象买回来
You have a moral responsibility
是要受到道德谴责的
to buy your killer elephant back.
那头小象呢
What about the baby?
至少它还逗笑了一些人
Well, at least he got a few laughs.
我要让他演小丑戏
I'll put him in the clown act,
看看还能不能补救一下
see if I can salvage something.
我出半价把它买回来
I'll buy her back half price.
你得出全额
You will buy her back full price.
四分之一的价钱
Quarter price.
半价就半价
Half price it is!
起来
Up!
发生什么事了  他们要带它去哪
What's happening? Where are they taking her?
走开  回到你的帐篷去
Away. Back to your tent now.
但它是小象的妈妈
But she's his mom!
爸爸  求你了  阻止他们
Dad, please. Stop them.
拜托
Please!
做点什么
Do something.
妈妈要在就会阻止他们
Mom would have done something.
你妈不在这里
Momma's not here.
好了  小家伙  过来吧
Okay, little fella. Okay. Come on.
我知道  我懂的
I know, I do.
美丽的生灵  我们会照顾好你的儿子
Beautiful creature, we'll take care of your son.
亲爱的  很晚了
Darlin', it's late.
去睡觉吧
Go on now.
我懂你  所以我也睡不着
I know. I can't sleep, either.
我妈妈告诉我总有一天
My momma told me there'd be times
我也会体会到被锁在门里的感觉
when my life seemed locked behind a door.
所以  她给了我这把钥匙
So, she gave me this key,
是我外婆给她的
that her momma gave her.
她说  每当我有这种感觉的时候
And said whenever I have that feeling,
就想象一下那扇门
imagine that door...
然后转动一下钥匙
and just turn the key.
所以  我一直在努力
So, I keep trying.
你不应该一个人来这里
Not supposed to be in here alone.
我不是一个人  你不是来了吗
I'm not. You're here.
那是什么
What's that?
我只是觉得它可能饿了
I just thought he might be hungry.
它很伤心
He's sad.
你伤心的时候也吃不下东西的
You don't eat when you're sad.
美人鱼就吃
The mermaid does.
来吧
Come on.
吃一口吧  呆宝
Have one, Dumbo.
我们要叫他呆宝吗
We're calling him Dumbo now?
如果我们叫他珍宝二号
If we call him Jumbo Junior...
它可能会想妈妈的
it might make him miss his mom.
干得好  呆宝
Here you go... Dumbo.
来吧  再拍一下耳朵
Come on, and flap those ears again.
表演一个我们意想不到的
To show us we didn't imagine it.
你妈妈  它并不想害任何人
Your momma, she didn't mean to hurt anyone.
它只是在保护你
She was just protecting you.
我们认为你的耳朵很棒
And we think your ears are great.
也许它想一个人呆着  像爸爸那样
Maybe he wants to be alone. Like Dad.
没有人真正想孤身一人
Nobody wants to be alone.
好吧
Well...
如果你改变主意了
if you change your mind...
晚安  呆宝
Night-night, Dumbo.
天啊
Wow!
这可不是花生让它飞起来的
It's not the peanuts that made him do it.
是羽毛
It's the feathers!
呆宝
Dumbo!
呆宝  你一定得表演这个
Dumbo, you gotta do this in the show.
什么意思
What do you mean?
如果马戏团能卖更多的票
'Cause if the circus sells more tickets
美第奇赚了更多的钱
and Medici makes more money...
我们就可以让他出钱
then we can get him to use some
把珍宝太太买回来
to buy Mrs. Jumbo back.
是啊
Yeah!
我们可以救你妈妈回来  呆宝
We can get her back, Dumbo.
你可以
You can.
让他们看看你的本事
Just show them all what you can do.
来吧  我们得告诉爸爸
Come on. We gotta tell Dad.
不  他只会跟我们说现实一点
No. He'll just tell us to be practical.
节目被取消了一个星期  对吗
Shows got canceled for a week, right?
我们还有时间研究  学习  测试
We can research and study and test.
你真是个神奇的小象  呆宝
You're a miracle elephant, Dumbo.
我们要带你妈妈回家了
And we're gonna bring your momma home.
开火
Fire!
太惨了
So low.
前所未有的惨
An all-time low.
谁说他不希望自己家喻户晓的
Who said he didn't want to be recognized?
好了大呆宝  就是现在
Okay, Big D, this is it.
就像排练那样
Just like in rehearsal.
别管那些灯光  音乐  火和人群
Except for lights, music, fire and crowds.
你可以做到  来吧  呆宝
You can do it. Come on, Dumbo.
你能做到的  呆宝
You can do it, Dumbo!
让他们开开眼界
Show 'em all like you showed us!
来吧  来吧  好样的  来吧
Come! Come! Come! Attaboy, come on.
继续前进  来吧
Keep comin'. Come on.
继续走  呆宝  继续
Go on now, Dumbo! Come on.
他们喜欢  他们喜欢
They love it! They love it!
好了  呆宝
All right, Dumbo.
你要把火扑灭了
You put out the fire.
它不敢飞  它很害怕
He won't fly. He's scared.
我知道  它站得太高了
I know. Now, he's up too high.
继续  呆宝
Go on, Dumbo!
好样的
Attaboy.
第一条规则
Yeah! Rule Number One.
结尾一定要华丽亮相
"Always have a big finish!"
好了  伙计们  把它放下来
Okay, guys. Bring him down.
霍特
Holt!
看  麦克斯  什么  什么
Look, Max! What? What?
它被困在那里  快把火扑灭
He's trapped up there. Put the fire out!
呆宝  飞啊
Dumbo! Fly!
没有羽毛它就不会飞
He won't fly without a feather!
快把火扑灭
Put the fire out!
把火给我灭了
Put it out!
乔  住手
Joe! Stop!
霍特  她上去干什么
Holt, I thought she didn't want to be in an act.
米莉
Milly!
给你  呆宝
Here, Dumbo!
来吧
Come on.
让他们看看
Show 'em.
来吧  呆宝
Come on, Dumbo.
飞吧  呆宝
Fly, Dumbo.
飞啊
Fly!
太好了
Yeah!
你知道它能飞吗
You knew he could do this?
你应该多和你的孩子们谈谈
You should talk to your kids more.
神奇大象因在
空中翱翔而出名
索斯比
Sotheby...
取消我和总统的晚餐
cancel my dinner with the president.
我们要去会会这头大象了
We've got business with an elephant.
朋友们
Friends,
接下来的演出会在阿肯色州
the next available shows are in Arkansas!
小丑们快乐
Happy clowns!
-荣格你好强壮  -老板
- Ah, Rongo the Strong! - Boss.
你好  乔
Hello, Jo!
美第奇兄弟马戏团
The Medici Brothers' circus.
真爱和神秘相伴的地方
Where true love and mystery abound!
我的明星在哪里
Now where's my star?
呆宝
Ah,  呆宝!
洗澡舒服么
How's your bath?
太热了  太冷了
Too warm? Too cold?
女士们  确保它的皱纹不要再长皱纹
Ladies, make sure his wrinkles don't get wrinkles.
在我们国家的传说中
In our country, legend tells us
神可以化身于动物体内
the gods can take animal forms.
为呆宝喝一杯
Champagne for Dumbo!
婴儿面前不准喝酒
No booze near the baby!
对不起  呆宝
Sorry, Dumbo.
不是你妈妈
It's not your momma.
把呆宝带回去
Take Dumbo back inside.
女士们先生们  请你们
Ladies and gentlemen, please make way
给这位迷人的国王
for the emperor of enchantment.
这位筑梦师
For the architect of dreams.
这位来自科尼岛的哥伦布的
For the Columbus of Coney Island.
V.A.范德维尔先生让路
Mr. V.A. Vandevere!
与他同行的  是他那闪亮的星星
And traveling with him, his bright shining star.
科莱特·玛茜特  天堂女王
Colette Marchant, the Queen of the Heavens!
玛茜特小姐  玛茜特小姐
Miss Marchant! Miss Marchant!
美第奇先生
Signore Medici!
他居然知道我是谁诶
He knows who I am.
我们刚好经过密苏里州
We were just passing through Missouri...
听说你们正要表演一个小节目
and we heard you were putting on a little show.
我很荣幸  范德维尔先生
Mr. Vandevere. It's an honor.
不  先生  是我的荣幸啊
No, sir. The honor is mine.
我想请你喝一杯
I would like to offer you a drink.
但我这儿已经没有波旁威士忌了
But I'm all out of bourbon.
干邑白兰地和苏格兰威士忌也没了
And cognac and scotch.
现在不是时候
Not now!
你抽屉里是有一只猴子吗
Is that a monkey in your desk?
只是以防万一罢了
Just for emergencies.
听着  范德维尔先生
Look, Mr. Vandevere...
我还是要事先说明
I probably should tell you...
我们是不会出售那只象的
the elephant is not for sale.
呆宝只会在美第奇马戏团表演
Dumbo will only fly for the Medici circus.
也就是说  他真的会飞
That's assuming he is real.
你自己看吧
See for yourself.
恕我直言  我没那么多时间和你们耗
And all due respect, I don't got all day.
-很荣幸能见到您  -借过
- Pleasure to meet you... - Excuse me.
你好啊
Hello there.
所以这个  你的这个生物…
So this, uh, creature of yours...
是可以飞的吗
is supposed to fly?
这是商业秘密
Trade secrets.
麦克斯  如果你不介意的话
Uh, Max, if you don't mind my asking...
你是在哪儿发现这只动物的
where did you come upon the animal?
他来自远东
He hails from the far east.
有多远
How far?
很远
Far.
它看上去可不像有什么所谓的魔法
He doesn't look like "magic" to me.
你光凭外表也得出些什么结论
Well, what the heck can you tell by appearances, right?
你也训练飞象吗
And you train flying elephants, too?
是的  一个小爱好而已
Yeah, it's a little hobby on the side.
呆宝是孩子们训练出来的
It's the kids taught Dumbo.
是的
Ah, yes.
对吧
Yeah?
但你们到底是怎么做到的
And how on earth did you do that?
用科学方法
With the scientific method.
一张照片  只能拍一张照片
One picture, one picture!
麦克斯
Max.
你拥有一样很罕见的东西
You possess something that's very rare in life.
可惜的是
And the tragedy of it is,
你没意识到这一点
is you don't even know that you have it.
你知道那样东西是什么吗  麦克斯
Do you know what it is that you have, Max?
不
No.
是神秘
It's mystique.
麦克斯  我知道你是什么样的人
Max, I know your type.
吹牛的  骗子  不劳而获的家伙
Charlatan, con man, opportunist...
如果你不知道  纽约就是这样子的
New York is that way, in case you need directions.
我知道  建立一些真实的东西
And I know it comes from a deep desire
是你的一种深深的渴望
to build something authentic and true.
我懂你的游戏规则
I know your game.
这不是游戏
It's not a game.
有些人不遵守规则  有些人改变规则
Some men cheat the rules, others change them.
它在你袖子里
It's up your sleeve.
不  是在你的口袋里
It's in your pocket.
你要是想随时随地就能表演魔术
The secret to show business
就要时刻留一只兔子在你的魔术帽里
is always keep a rabbit in your hat.
或者就像你在桌子里放的猴子一样
Or a monkey in your desk, I guess.
这是  所有权的股份
Ownership shares?
麦克斯  看看你周围吧
Max, look around you.
你的整个生活方式都快无聊死了
Your entire way of life is dying.
娱乐业的未来
The future of the entertainment business
就是得把要观众带到你面前
is to bring the audience to you.
我建造了那个地方
And I've built that destination.
而我只缺
What I'm lacking...
一个门生
is a protege.
我知道你其实没有兄弟
I know there's no Medici Brothers.
你可能一直挺想要一个的吧
You probably always wanted one.
你这是要和我合作的意思吗
You're offering me a partnership?
对
Yes.
还有给你和你剧团的
And a home.
一个家
For you and the entire troupe.
一个家吗  给我们所有人吗
A home? For all of us?
对  和我合作吧
Yes. Join me.
和我合作吧  成为我们的家人吧
Join me and my family.
让我带领大家实现未来
Let me take us all into the future.
让我带大家进入
Let me take us all...
梦幻之地
to Dreamland!
我真希望妈妈也能看到这个
I wish Momma could've seen this.
不知怎的  我总觉得她知道我们在这里
Well, somehow, I think she knows we're here.
这是你的魔术梦想之路啊  麦克斯
Way to work your magic, Max.
我们听到你在叫了  呆宝
We hear you, Dumbo!
你为什么不让他看看外面
Why won't you let him see outside?
要记住  小姐
Remember, young lady...
保持神秘
mystique.
这就是我加入马戏团的原因
Now this is why I joined the circus.
爸爸  这都是科学奇迹
Dad. Wonders of Science!
好吧  我的小糖果
All right, sugar plum.
别忘了  我们是来这工作的
Remember, we got a job to do here.
这是我女儿
My daughter,
她总是想象自己是下一个居里夫人
she fancies herself the next Marie Curie.
不要让别人来告诉你  你做不到
Don't ever let anybody tell you what you can't do.
等等  我没说她做不到啊
Hang on, I wasn't saying she can't.
我们在这儿是为了干什么  夫人
What is it exactly that we do here, ma cherie?
我们使不可能成为可能
We make the impossible possible.
这就是你要表演的地方
And that's where you'll perform.
奇幻竞技场
The Colosseum!
呆宝会呆在后面的训练帐篷里
Dumbo will stay in the training tent behind.
呆宝
Dumbo!
我们为什么不和他一起去
Why aren't we going with him?
因为那个才是你的新家
Because that is your new home.
看看这儿啊
Look at this place!
一个图书馆
A library...
"孩子们将引领他们"
"And the children shall lead them."
改自《以赛亚书》第11章6节
我们很感激这次机会  范德维尔先生
We're grateful for the opportunity, Mr. Vandevere.
别这么说  我们已经是个大家庭了
Oh, your family's mine.
法瑞尔先生  我总是能耳闻您的故事
You know, I've been brushing up on your story, Mr. Farrier.
您是肯塔基州最好的特技骑手
Kentucky's top trick rider.
所以  您在这儿也肯定一样是的
Well, there's no reason you can't be again...
唯一不同的是  您是法瑞尔上尉
only here, you'd be Captain Farrier...
一个战争英雄
war hero.
一个独臂人的奇迹
One-armed wonder.
堪称国宝
National treasure.
我还是能骑的
Well, I still can ride.
我知道你能
Oh, I know you can.
而且你一定要骑
And you're going to.
就在你得到那只小象之后
Right after you get that little elephant
然后要从地上飞起来
off the ground for me.
是在它成功地完成演出的情况下吗
You mean once his act's working?
没错  看来你已经准备好了
You're back in the saddle.
你剧团剩下的成员
We're still working on the schedule
会依旧按计划工作
for the rest of your troupe...
但是星期五
but on Friday...
就是我们的呆宝首演的日子
we premiere our little Dumbo.
我兴奋得都起鸡皮疙瘩了
I get goose bumps.
你为什么看着我
Why are you looking at me?
因为只有一样东西
Well, because the only thing
比飞象更神奇
more amazing than a flying elephant...
那就是能够骑着它飞的女神
is the goddess who can fly it.
你是疯了吧
Have you lost your mind?
别忘了我们是从哪儿来的  亲爱的
Let's not forget from whence we came, darling.
好了  所以我们会在周五试飞
So, we fly Friday!
呆宝从来没有载人飞行过
Uh, Dumbo's never flown with anyone.
已经很明显了  这就是为什么
That's why it's become abundantly clear
我们需要你
why we need you.
呆宝
Dumbo!
伙计  我们想死你了  你还好吗
Hey, buddy. We missed you. You all right?
法瑞尔上尉负责这只呆宝了
Hey. Captain Farrier is in charge.
未经他同意  任何人都不能见这只动物
No one sees the animal without his approval.
霍特
Holt.
就叫我霍特吧
Just call me Holt.
我以为你是个军人
I thought you were a military man.
你的靴子很漂亮  是鲨鱼皮的吗
Nice boots you bagged there. What are they, shark skin?
不
No.
所以  你最好让你的大象朋友
So you better keep your elephant friend
表现好点儿
on my good side.
你好  呆宝
Hiya, Dumbo.
呆宝  你介意
Dumbo, you mind?
把我胳膊松开吗
Can I get my arm?
这就是我要交予生命来换取的那双手吗
And these are the hands I'll be putting my life in?
欢迎
Welcome.
提前说一声  这不是我的主意
For the record, this was not my idea.
呆宝一般自己飞
Dumbo works alone.
我也是
So do I.
你好  米莉  乔
Bonjour, Milly, Joe...
还有你
And you...
很迷人
Hmm, charming.
嗯  也许是因为他认不出来
Well, maybe he doesn't recognize you
没化妆的你
without your makeup.
所以我要教你飞
So I gotta teach you to fly?
我从小就知道怎么飞了
I know how to fly, ever since I was a child.
他们教呆宝飞  不是吗
They taught Dumbo to fly, no?
所以我不需要你的那些专业知识
So I don't need your expertise.
好吧
All right.
就告诉你一下  我去过法国
Well, just so you know, I've been to France.
那可不是一次美好的经历
It wasn't a good experience.
告诉我你的秘密吧
Show me your secret!
你的大象到底是怎么飞的
How on earth does your elephant fly?
首先  他需要一根羽毛
Well, first, he needs a feather.
没有羽毛他就飞不了
He won't fly without a feather.
那么  我也不行
Well then, neither will I.
公主慢点儿   安全第一
Whoa, slow down, princess. Safety first.
伙计们  网子拉上
Guys, nets.
来吧  快点儿
Come on, hurry.
可以了  伙计们
All right, guys, good.
呆宝看到了吗
See, Dumbo?
我飞起来了
I fly!
试试看能不能抓到我
See if you can catch me!
给你羽毛  呆宝
Here, Dumbo!
咱们可有的练了
Oh, we got some work to do.
朋友们  同事们
Friends and colleagues...
让我们把梦幻之地式的热烈欢迎
let's give a warm Dreamland welcome
送给我们的新执行副总裁
to our new executive vice president...
麦克斯·美第奇先生
Mr. Max Medici.
他需要的一切
Anything he needs, anything at all...
请你们像往常一样帮他完成
make it happen as you always do.
这是维娜小姐
This is Miss Verna.
她会处理你的日程  书信  以及电话
She will handle your schedule, correspondence, and all your calls.
如果有会议需要你的话
When you're needed in meetings,
她会通知你
she'll let you know.
今天就有会吗
Are there meetings today?
我会通知你的
I'll let you know!
范德维尔先生  我还有个问题
Uh, Mr. Vandevere, one question.
我到底是干什么的
Exactly what do I do?
范德维尔是在哪里找到你的
So where'd Vandevere find you?
我曾经在巴黎街头表演
I was a street performer in Paris.
他发掘了我
He discovered me.
然后我就到这儿来了
And here I am.
然后就成了百万富翁的女友
A millionaire's girlfriend.
可真是个重大的转变啊
That's a tough break.
全都是逢场作戏而已
It's all for show.
所以你们不是
So you and he, you're not, uh...
我只是他满身的饰品之一
I'm one of many gems he wears
用来把舞台灯聚焦到他身上
to reflect the light back onto him.
干得漂亮呆宝
Good boy, Dumbo.
干得不错  观众会喜欢他的
Good job. Yeah! They're gonna love him.
看来你才是幸运的那个
I think you are the lucky one.
呆宝你真棒  好孩子
Well done, Dumbo. Good boy.
♪ 是谁做着和我同样的梦 ♪
♪ Who's been dreaming like I've been dreaming? ♪
这边怎么样  还顺利吗
So, how's everything? Good?
我们有点进展了
Oh, we're making progress.
但它还没怎么准备好
But he ain't quite ready yet.
哪儿出问题了  这动物不信任你吗
What's the problem? Doesn't the animal trust you?
这没那么简单
It's not that simple.
我亲爱的  我们票都已经卖光了
Ma cherie...we've already sold all the tickets.
没准我们这儿的小科学家
Maybe our little scientist here
能为我们展示顺利的表演
can show us that it's going to work.
起飞预备
Prepare for takeoff.
右翼检查
Right wing? Check!
左翼检查
Left wing? Check!
载她起飞呆宝
Take her up, Dumbo.
来吧
Let's go.
加油呆宝  加油
Come on, buddy. Come on. Come on, Dumbo.
好的  加油
That's it. Come on.
我们再试一次
Let's try it again.
你可以的  羽毛给你
You got this. Here you go.
你是我见过最酷的独臂牛仔
You beautiful one-armed cowboy.
你让我感觉自己又是个孩子了
You've made me a child again.
欢迎来到奇幻竞技场
Welcome to the Colosseum...
在这里点石可成金  枯木能生花
where the impossible is possible.
晚上好  我是麦克斯·美第奇
Buonasera. Max Medici.
是我发现了那头大象  那是我的象
I discovered the elephant, my elephant.
然后我就说了不
And basically I said no.
我走了出去 然后就结束了
I walked out and that was the end of that.
那头能飞的大象是我的
The flying elephant's mine.
你就是那个人
You're the guy!
你就是那个有魔法的人
You're the guy that's made out of magic dust!
麦克斯
Max.
这位是来自亚特拉斯制造银行
J. Griffin Remington.
的J·格里芬·雷明顿
Atlas Forge Bank.
他是我们的金主
He's the money man.
你就是那位J
The J?
很荣幸见到您
Whoa! It's a pleasure to meet you.
你好
How are you?
有人说月亮是有魔法的
You know, they say the moon is made out of magic dust.
所以他们最近才要
That's why they're going to
送个人上去
send a man up there one of these days.
而我的银行就是那个
And my bank is going to be the bank
赞助这次探索的银行
that finances the expedition.
有什么评价吗
What do you think of that?
麦克斯  毫无疑问的是
Needless to say, Max...
我们都很期待今晚的表演
we all have high hopes for tonight.
我明白  你们当然都很期待
Oh, yeah. High hopes. High hopes.
期望啊  梦想啊
Well, you know, hopes, and dreams,
都只是一方面  一些空泛的词语而已
that's one thing. That's words.
但我们在这里讨论的是事实和计划
But what we're talking about here is facts! Plans!
那些需要的是真金白银
Plans! That takes a lot of money.
而他没钱
Which he hasn't got!
所以我们希望你的厚皮怪
So, we are hoping that your pachyderm
能顺利表演  赚一大笔钱
comes through with the goods.
那么现在让表演开始吧
Now let's get this show on the road!
我们都准备好了
We are looking good!
别担心大呆宝
Don't worry, Big D.
这里只是让你能敞开了飞而已  没什么
There's just more room to fly out there, that's all.
就飞几圈  像我们练习的那样
Round and round, just like we practiced.
然后老爸就能跟范德维尔
And then Dad can talk
谈谈我们的约定了
to Vandevere about the deal!
谈什么
About the what?
我们和呆宝有个约定
We made a deal with Dumbo.
我们跟它保证了会把它妈妈买回来
We promised we'd buy his mom back
用它在马戏团里挣得钱
with all the money he makes for the circus.
所以他才同意表演
That's why he flies.
乔现在不是谈这个的时候
Joe, not now!
准备好了吗
Are we ready?
当然
Yeah.
祝我们好运
Bonne chance.
好的  我们上
Okay, let's go.
呆宝  出发了
Okay, Dumbo, let's do this.
粉色的大象
Pink elephants?
怎么了
So?
女士们先生们  大朋友们小朋友们
Ladies and gentlemen, boys and girls of all ages!
我们等待已久的时刻终于到了
This is the moment we've all been waiting for!
V.A. 范德维尔
V.A. Vandevere,
和麦克斯·美第奇一道
in association with Max Medici...
骄傲地为您呈现
proudly presents, making his Dreamland debut...
也许你见过小飞马
You've seen a horse-fly.
也许你见过小飞龙
You've seen a dragonfly.
也许你甚至见过小飞屋
You've even seen a housefly.
但你依然还没见过某些东西
But you haven't seen anything...
直到你见到了小飞象
until you see an elephant fly.
让我们欢迎  呆宝
Let's get ready for Dumbo!
借光
Coming through.
过来
Come on.
它能做到
He can do it.
他肯定可以
I know he can.
然后让我们欢迎这位
And here to welcome him...
我们的天国女王
our own Queen of the Heavens!
呆宝
Dumbo.
我们只要绕着这儿飞五圈就好了
Five times around the ring. That's all we have to do.
慢慢来  像我们排练的那样
Nice and easy, like we practiced.
-老爸  -怎么
-Dad? - Mmm-hmm.
他们为什么没把网子拉起来
Why aren't they putting up the nets?
嘿  朋友们
Hey, guys?
什么情况
Guys, what's going on?
你们本来应该在外面
Your men are supposed to be out there!
上面有话  计划有变
Change of plan. From the top.
没把网子拉起来吗
I can't see the nets.
聪明的人才看得见
They're invisible.
你们有毛病吗  他们需要这些网
What's wrong with you? They need nets!
科莱特
Colette!
等下  先别飞
Wait, don't take off!
呆宝
Dumbo...
天呐  不好了
Oh, boy!
象国之子
...Prince of the Elephants.
请你和我一起飞翔
I command you to fly with me.
科莱特
Colette!
快把平台降下来
Lower the platform!
飞啊  孩子
Fly, little one!
这是就魔法
Magic dust!
我的精彩演出呢
Where's my show?
那头大象往噩梦岛去了
The elephant's headed to Nightmare Island.
来吧宝贝  咱们离开这儿
Come on, sweetie. Let's go.
呆宝  别害怕
Dumbo, it's okay.
有我们在这儿
We're here.
晚上好
Good evening.
是范德维尔先生
It's Mr. Vandevere.
大家好
Hello, hi.
玩的都还开心吗
Everyone having fun?
太好了
Good.
-开心吗  -开心极了
- Having a good time? - Yes, sir.
完美
Fantastic.
把它弄出去
Get him outta here.
好的
Yes.
大家请跟我来
Folks, please.
请大家先离开这里
Folks, I need you to leave the exhibit.
过来
Come on.
你们轻点儿  他还是个孩子
Guys, guys, go easy, he's just a baby.
士兵  在这里要听我的命令
Soldier, I give the orders here.
他该睡觉了
It's his bedtime.
此景点现已关闭
This attraction is now closed.
爸爸
Dad?
她是珍宝夫人
It's Mrs. Jumbo.
拜托  我想看呆宝
Come on, I want to see Dumbo!
我想要回我的猴子
I want my money back!
我不明白
I don't understand.
大象居然能飞  你也看到了
The elephant flies. You saw it.
我什么也没看到
I saw a vanishing act.
除非我看到表演  我才会投资
I'm not investing one cent until I can see this works.
你甚至控制不了你的动物
You can't control your animal.
给我点时间  我会处理好的
You give me a little time, I can fix this.
随便你  处理好之前别想拿到一分钱
Whatever! Till then, the bank is closed.
刚刚是怎么回事
What happened up there?
你的动物失控了
You lost control of the animal.
你才是动物
You're the animal.
我的网呢
Where was my net?
网是用来排练的  这可是表演
Nets are for rehearsal. This is the show.
练习  你说这是练习
Training? You call that training?
别急  范德维尔先生
Now, hold on, Mr. Vandevere,
我们知道他为什么会飞走
we know why he flew away.
他听到了另一头大象的呼唤
He recognized that other elephant's call.
就是被关在噩梦岛的    他的妈妈
The one on Nightmare Island. It's his momma!
是真的  是她
It's true. It's her.
两个月前她从我们马戏团卖出去了
She was sold from our circus two months ago.
每个孩子都能认出自己的妈妈
Every child knows its mother.
听说大象记忆力很好
And they say elephants never forget.
他们现在可以在一起了
They can be together now.
这两个小孩怎么会在我办公室
Why are there children in my office?
范德维尔先生求你了  呆宝需要妈妈
Mr. Vandevere, please, all Dumbo wants is his momma.
让他们团聚吧
Just reunite them,
他会服从你的命令
and he'll do whatever you want.
错  他只听他妈妈的话
No, he'll do whatever she wants.
你以为如果我相信他们的血缘关系
You think I'd have bought her
我就要买下她吗
if I thought she was related to him? Hmm?
这对我根本没有好处
Doesn't help me at all.
你们想知道成长中
You wanna know the most important thing
最重要的事是什么吗？
about growing up?
你必须学会独自一人
You've got to learn to go it alone.
把那个母亲挪走  你知道她在哪里
Get rid of the mother. You know where to take her.
还有就是给你自己买双新靴子
And treat yourself to some new boots.
但是先生  你不能杀了她
But, sir, you can't just kill her.
为什么不行
Why not?
范德维尔先生
Mr. Vandevere.
请等等  请不要分开他们
Wait! Don't separate 'em, please.
不要这样对我的孩子
Don't do that to my kids.
你知道吗  霍特  我父亲离开我时
You know, Holt, when my father left us,
对我来说其实是件好事
it was a blessing really.
因为我必须学会自力更生
Because I had to learn how to fend for myself.
你的孩子可能也需如此
Maybe that's what your children need.
别跟我说我的孩子需要什么
Don't tell me what my children need.
别靠这么近  养象人
Best take a step back, Elephant Man.
亲爱的
Darling...
呆宝要和他妈妈分开一段时间
Dumbo and his mom need a little alone time.
所以  妈妈会离开几天
So, Mommy's going to take a little trip...
这样呆宝就不会分心了
so that Dumbo won't be distracted.
米莉  米莉
Milly! Milly!
科莱特
Colette?
我还要排练
I have rehearsal.
麦克斯
Max.
噩梦岛
Nightmare Island.
米莉
Milly?
世上最危险的野兽的家园
Home of the most dangerous beasts in the world.
先生  景点关门了
Sir, park's closing.
米莉  米莉
Milly! Milly!
找到她了吗
Did you find her?
没有
No.
她妈妈总是知道该怎么办
Well, her momma always knew what to say.
任何情况下她都知道
No matter what, she always knew.
你的孩子不需要你很完美
Your children don't need you to be perfect.
他们只需要你的信任
They just need you to believe in them.
就这么简单  是吗
That simple, huh?
好吧  我再找找
All right, well, I'm gonna keep looking.
那是我女儿吗
That's my daughter all right.
我认识的唯一一个离家上学的女孩
The only girl I know who runs away to go to school.
是我们的错
It's our fault.
呆宝肯定希望不曾遇到过我们
Bet Dumbo wishes he never met us.
不  你让他学会了飞翔
Ah, you showed him he could fly.
你认为他会靠这个赚钱吗
You think he'd ever trade that?
他只想要他妈妈回来
He would to have his mom back.
我想妈妈了
I miss Momma.
我也想她了
Yeah, so do I.
给你看些东西
There's something I want to show you.
随着工程学和医学的进步
With advances in both engineering and medicine...
不久之后人类和机器就能共同
the human and the mechanical will soon be combined...
协助普通家庭  工人和退伍军人
to assist ordinary families, workers and veterans.
无数科技奇迹
All kinds of technological marvels
在20世纪等着我们
await us in the 20th century.
你会做得很好的
You're gonna do great things.
宏伟而又光明的未来
我相信你
I know it.
这是什么
Whoa, whoa. What's this?
让我休息一下
Oh, give me a break.
我难道要教你怎么读英语吗
I gotta teach you how to read English, too?
梦幻之地的飞象失控了吗
你好  麦克斯
Oh, Max, hello!
很好  你把文件带来了
Good, you brought the paperwork.
麦克斯
Max...
我在回顾你的演出
I was reviewing your troupe...
老实说
and to be honest with you...
他们模仿我们的动作一点也不像
they're really pale imitations from the acts we already have.
所以我在考虑  也许
So I was thinking, I don't know,
一个月的遣散费  够公平吧
a month's severance? Seems fair.
明白了吗
Capisce?
Capisce为意大利语
我以为你答应了
I thought you promised to...
麦克斯  事实证明我得解雇他们
Max, the contract says that I'd hire them.
而我从没规定雇佣期限
It never stipulated for how long.
所以  把你那群廉价的疯子带出去
So, get your little band of low-rent freaks out of here.
但他们是我的剧团  他们在等我
But they're my troupe. They're countin' on me.
好吧  那就公开布诚
Okay, let's have a heart.
你为什么不直接告诉他们呢
Why don't you tell them?
老板  我们什么时候开始
'Bout time, boss. So, when do we start?
怎么了
What's going on, guys?
他们被范德维尔解雇了
Vandevere's fired them all.
明天就得离开
They're to leave by tomorrow.
再见  小可爱
Goodbye, little friend.
再见
Goodbye.
我们想最后看一次
We wanted to see him one last time.
最后看他飞一次
One last time to see him fly.
我觉得他不想再飞了
I don't think he wants to anymore.
别这样  他必须要飞
Oh, no. But he must.
他不能再次失去他的妈妈
He cannot lose Mrs. Jumbo again!
这还不是最糟糕的
Uh, I'm afraid it's rather worse than that.
索斯比先生
Mr. Sotheby?
出于良心的谴责
I've come to clear my conscience.
我一听到他的指令我就辞职了
I resigned my position as soon as I heard him give the order.
什么指令
What order?
珍宝夫人明晚要被送走了
Mrs. Jumbo will be gone by tomorrow night.
没人能救她
And she's not meant to survive.
梦幻之地配不上他
This "Dreamland" doesn't deserve him.
没有马戏团配得上
No circus does.
谁愿意帮我
Well, who's gonna be willing to help me?
让呆宝和他妈妈重获自由
Set Dumbo and his momma free.
欢迎来到奇幻竞技场
Welcome to the Colosseum,
这里点石可成金  朽木能生花
where the impossible is possible.
好吧  第二次被吸引来
Okay. Second time's the charm.
让我们看看梦之父表现如何
Let's see if Dream Daddy's worked out the kinks.
我们要从噩梦岛带大象出去
Here to pick up the elephant from Nightmare Island.
收到
Confirmed.
打开后门
Unlock the back gates.
噩梦岛
后门
呆宝就位
Dumbo in position!
他一飞  你们就跑回他的帐篷
Soon as he flies, you run back to his tent
我会去那里找你们
and I'll find you there.
别担心  大呆宝
All right, Big D.
就看你的了
It's all up to you now.
加油  霍特
Come on, Holt!
见鬼去吧
To hell with it.
准备就位
Ready for positions.
我们应该排练一下
We could have used a little rehearsal.
排练
Rehearsal?
我们在阿尔贡战役中有预演吗
Think we got a rehearsal at the Battle of the Argonne?
一战著名战役,此次战役协约国大获全胜
你确定你可以吗
You sure you can do this?
我很有经验
I fly elephants all the time.
你确定你做得到吗
Are you sure you can do this?
就算绑上一只手也完全没问题
With one hand tied behind my back.
等等  谁在那
Wait. What's that?
女士
Ma'am?
抱歉  女士  景点关门了
Sorry, ma'am, attraction's closed.
我梦想  成为美人鱼
My dream... to be a mermaid...
但是现在他们夺走了我的梦想
and now they've taken it away.
我听见海水在歌唱
And yet I hear the water singing.
听见他们在唤我回家
I hear them beckoning me home.
女士  小心一点好吗
Lady, just be careful, okay?
把我带回广阔的深渊
Return me to the vast abyss!
我们走
Let's go.
-我的命运  回归大海  -好了
- My destiny, the sea! - Okay.
停电了
We've lost power!
笼子的锁也失效了
Even the cages?
这些动物
But the animals...
找到断电的地方  把灯打开
Find the breakers. Get the lights back on!
确保所有笼子都锁着
And make sure those cages are locked.
女士们  先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
男孩们  女孩们
boys and girls.
这是他第二次在梦幻之地亮相
Making his second Dreamland debut.
让我们准备好迎接呆宝吧
Let's get ready for Dumbo!
这是个骗局  给我回到
It's a trick! Get back to the...
再一次  我们自己的天堂女王出场
And once again, our very own Queen of the Heavens!
你
You.
你的怪胎马戏团在哪
Where is your circus of freaks?
发生什么事
What's going on?
大象的妈妈不见了
The elephant's mother is gone!
他的戏团搞的鬼
His troupe's behind it!
警戒塔台  防守大门
Alert the tower and secure the gates.
别让他们出去
Don't let them get out.
但他们为什么只带走这一头呢
But why would they only take the one?
看好法瑞尔和那俩孩子
Keep your eye on Farrier and those kids.
你  跟我们来
You! Come with us.
他们在那
There they are!
嘿  你
Hey, you!
你在上面干什么
What are you doing up there?
那是私人财产
That's private property.
快点  下来
Come on! Get down here!
马上
Now!
嘿  我是麦克斯·美第奇
Hey, I'm Max Medici,
范德维尔的搭档
Vandevere's partner.
他只是个修理工在修灯
He's just a maintenance man fixing a light!
回到你的岗位上去
Get back to your posts!
是的  美第奇先生
Yes, sir, Mr. Medici.
让我们再试一次
Let's try this again.
你和我
You and me.
孩子们呢
Hey, the kids?
孩子们在哪
Where are the kids?
你见过孩子们吗
Hey, have you seen the kids?
呆宝  大象王子
Dumbo, Prince of the Elephants!
我命令你和我一起飞行
I command you to fly with me.
呆宝  拜托了快飞
Dumbo, please fly.
为你的妈妈飞
Do it for your momma.
你们的父亲在哪
Where's your father?
呆宝
Dumbo!
嘿  抓住那俩孩子
Hey! Get those kids!
呆宝去那
Dumbo!
走吧
Come on.
那儿
There!
您好
Bonsoir.
只是路过
Just passing through!
你不能那样做
Hey! You can't do that!
抓住大象
Get the elephant!
你去抓大象
You get the elephant!
别担心  爸爸很快就到
Don't worry. Dad'll be here soon.
大象在哪
Where's the elephant?
你怎么还傻站在那
Why are you just standing there?
到塔台上去
Get to the tower!
停电了  没有电梯
Electricity's failing! There's no elevators!
据我所知  他们发明了楼梯
When I last checked, they invented stairs.
我们似乎遇到了一些技术故障
We seem to be experiencing some technical difficulties.
我的电力是怎么了
What happened to my power?
什么权力  亲爱的
What power, mon cheri?
你这忘恩负义的
You ungrateful...
你以前什么都不是  在我把你变成我的
You were nothing before I made you my... Uh...
我相信这个词是  女王
I believe the word is "queen."
我需要灯
I need lights!
范德维尔先生  等等
Mr. Vandevere, wait!
我们必须重置电源  否则会引发浪涌
We have to reset the mains, or you could cause a surge!
现在是不可能的
Right now it's impossible!
没有什么是不可能的
Nothing's impossible!
范德维尔先生
Mr. Vandevere!
范德维尔先生  停下
Mr. Vandevere, stop!
米莉  乔
Milly! Joe!
来吧  走  快点
Come on. Go! Come on!
所有人都出来
Get everyone out!
从公园撤离
Evacuate the park!
米莉  乔
Milly! Joe!
大象在哪
Where is the elephant?
放开她
Let her go!
快点
Come on!
米莉  乔
Milly! Joe!
爸爸
Dad!
-你们还好吧  -我们没事
- You all right? - All right? We're fine.
好  快点  遮住脸
Okay, come on. All right, cover your faces.
把手给我  快点
Give me your hand! Come on!
后退
Back!
别分散
Stay close.
来吧  大伙
Come on, everybody.
我们现在去海港吧
Let's get to the seaport! Now!
法瑞尔一家在哪里
Where are the Farriers?
他们一定还在里面
They must still be inside.
爸爸
Dad!
没事的  乔
It's okay, Joe.
过来  过来
Come here. Come here.
呆宝
Dumbo!
快来
Come on!
走 走  快去  跳
Go! Go! Go! Go! Jump!
过来  过来
Come on. Come on.
好了  我们走吧  跟紧点  快点
All right, let's go. Stay close, come on.
好了  快走  快走
Okay. Go! Go! Go!
快点
Come on!
呆宝  快来
Dumbo! Come on!
呆宝  怎么了
Dumbo! What's wrong?
伙计们
Guys!
米莉  乔  快点
Milly! Joe! Come on!
呆宝  我们走
Dumbo, let's go!
走
Go!
呆宝
Dumbo!
抓住他
Get him!
他看到我们了
He's seen us.
呆宝  你得走了
Dumbo, you gotta go.
他们要来抓你
They're comin' for you.
你得走了  呆宝
You gotta go, Dumbo.
他的羽毛丢了
He lost the feather.
羽毛没什么用
Feather doesn't do nothin'.
呆宝  你不需要羽毛就能飞
Dumbo, you don't need the feather to fly.
爸爸  他们来了
Dad, they're coming!
退后  退后
Stand back! Stand back!
让开
Out of my way!
呆宝  还记这个吗
Dumbo, remember this?
我从妈妈那里得到的
From my momma?
我可以打开任何门  你也可以
I can unlock any door. And you can, too.
但我不需要这把钥匙就能做到
But I don't need this key to do it.
而你也不需要羽毛
And you don't need the feather.
来吧
Come on.
爸爸
Dad!
得走了  快点
Gotta go. Come on!
你干嘛
What are you doing?
象背上不够三个人坐的
There ain't room for the three of us.
你带他去海港  我们在那儿见
You get him to the seaport and I'll see you there.
走吧  大呆宝
Go on, Big D.
抓住他们
Grab 'em!
那是我的大象
That's my elephant!
他们安全了
They're safe.
快点  我们走
Come on, let's go!
嘿  回来
Hey! Get back here!
你这个畸形  你做了什么
You freak! What have you done?
他们为此付我钱  先生
What they pay me for, mister.
上演一场精彩的演出
Put on a hell of a show.
他
Hey! Him!
就那个  逮捕那个人
Right there, arrest that man.
他偷了我的大象
He stole my elephant.
我们有合同  美第奇
Hey, we had a contract, Medici!
我不是专家
I'm no expert,
但我认为你这里有更大的问题
but I think you got bigger problems here.
这真是一场灾难
Wow. This is a disaster.
来吧  我请你吃热狗
Come on, I'll buy you a hot dog.
听起来不错  J.G.
Sounds good, J.G.
骗子之地
最后装货提醒
Last call for cargo!
全部上船
All aboard!
科莱特
Colette!
你父亲在哪
Where's your father?
别担心  他会赶到的
Don't worry. He'll be here.
爸爸
Dad!
我就知道你们会骑象
I knew you could ride.
普拉德什  我们得走了
Pramesh, we have to go.
拜托  快点
Please, hurry.
快点  赶紧  快点
Hurry! Come on! Hurry!
来吧
Come.
我们回家吧
Let's go home.
快走吧  你个小捣蛋鬼
Well, get out of here, you little troublemaker.
走吧
Go on.
女士们  先生们
Ladies and gentlemen...
我为你们介绍我们世界著名的飞象
introducing our world-famous flying elephant.
欢迎来到美第奇家族马戏团
Welcome to the Medici Family circus!
我们相信没有野生动物
Where we believe no wild animals
应该被关起来
shall be held in captivity.
地球上最棒的小型演出
看看荣格
See Rongo...
世界上最强壮最多才多艺的人
the world's strongest and most versatile man.
认识一下迷人的亚特兰蒂斯小姐
Meet the bewitching Miss Atlantis...
她正在表演水下莎士比亚
now performing underwater Shakespeare,
和世界上唯一活着的人鱼普克一起
with the world's only living merman, Puck!
呼吸  还是不呼吸
参观我们最新的景点
And visit our newest attraction,
米莉·法瑞尔的奇妙世界
Milly Farrier's World of Wonders...
去发现所有真实存在的奇观
to discover all the real-life amazements
在今天塑造明天
that are shaping tomorrow today!
惊叹于传奇的霍特的骑术
Marvel at the skills of the legendary Holt...
我们的未来牛仔
our cowboy of the future!
以及巴黎珍珠  科莱特
And the Pearl of Paris, Colette.
天堂女王
Queen of the Heavens!
朋友们  无论老少
Friends, young and old,
你在我们的马戏团都有个家
you have a home at our circus.
在这里一切皆有可能
Where anything is possible
是奇迹发生的地方
and miracles happen.
相信我  真的会发生
Believe me, they do.
美第奇家族马戏团
本片终